<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="t.cservenak@gmail.com">CSERVENAK, Tamas</author>
    <title>Deployment Guide</title>
  </properties>

<head>
  <meta name="keywords" content="abstracthorizon, abstract horizon, proximity, proxy, maven proxy, build management systems, build systems, build tools, enterprise build software, enterprise build tools, build automation, maven, mvn, maven2, continuous integration, java"/>
  <meta name="description" content="Proximity - the proactive mirror"/>
</head>

<body>

<section name="Deployment guide">

<p>This Guide is <b>work in progress</b>.</p>

<p>The prepackaged WARs comes with following general configurations (for details see 
<a href="factory-conf.html">Proximity Default Configuration</a>):</p>

<ul>
<li>The root of proximity storages are in <b>user home</b> directory.</li>
</ul>

<p>Since Proximity uses SLF4J project for logging, see 
<a href="http://slf4j.org/">SLF4J Site</a> for additional logging configuration possibilities.</p>

<p>Now, we will see some web container specific tasks for Proximity deployment.</p>

<subsection name="Apache Tomcat">

<p>Proximity has been extensively tested on Tomcat 5.5.x line. For deployment on Tomcat, you simply need 
to "drop" the WAR file in $CATALINA_HOME/webapps directory. Proximity may have problems with
logging, see SLF4J documentation about it. You may need some additional steps:</p>

<ul>
<li>If you can, remove log4j.jar from Tomcat installation, or swap logger implementation during deployment,
as described on SLF4J site.</li>
</ul>

<p>Advanced users may <b>unpack</b> the WAR and gain access to configuration files. Also, please
review the logging settings (nLog4j currently), since it may not be suited your needs!</p>

</subsection>

<subsection name="Jetty">

<p>Proximity has been extensively tested on Jetty 5.1.11 line. For deployment on Jetty, you need some
additional steps:</p>

<ul>
<li>Remove XercesImpl-2.6.2.jar from WAR, since it conflicts with Jetty's one.</li>
</ul>

<p>Finally, simply "drop" the WAR file in $JETTY_HOME/webapps directory.</p>

<p>Advanced users may <b>unpack</b> the WAR and gain access to configuration files. Also, please
review the logging settings (Log4j currently), since it may not be suited your needs!</p>

<p><b>NOTE:</b> On unreleased Jetty6 no steps are reqiured to deploy Proximity.</p>

</subsection>

</section>

</body>
</document>
