<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="cservenak@is-micro.hu">CSERVENAK, Tamas</author>
    <title>ISmicro Projects</title>
  </properties>

  <meta name="keyword" content="ismicro java"/>

<body>

<section name="Proximity">

<p>Proximity is a proxy-like pure Java application.</p>

<p>Proximity consists of PX Core module, which is the "headless" Proximity 
itself made<b>environment and transport independent</b>, so it is capable to 
run in J2SE and J2EE environment too.</p>

<p>The PX Webapp is a thin J2EE Webapp (2 controller classes + some Velocity 
templates!) built upon Spring IoC framework and it's MVC implementation, and 
makes the Proximity Servlet implementation.</p>

<subsection name="Using Proximity as corporate Maven proxy">
<p>The initial goal to develop Proximity was to make some alternative to
the existing <a href="http://maven-proxy.codehaus.org">maven-proxy</a> 
application on Codehaus.</p>

<p>The Proximity has the following features, that enables it to act as
Maven-aware caching proxy:</p>

<ul>
<li>With extensible proxying logic it is able to handle maven artifacts in 
"maven-way" (there is a Logic implementation out-of-the-box)</li>
<li>It is possible to define more remote repositories, thus Proximity is
aggregating these repositores and also is caching the and reduces outbound
traffic.</li>
<li>The flexibility to define repositories allows administrator to include
a local only repository to publish in-house artifacts, or other commercial
artifacts that are not found or ibiblio or other mainstream maven repo.</li>
</ul>

<p>In contrast to the maven-proxy implementation:</p>
<ul>
<li>Proximity Core is transport and environment independent (no javax.* deps) and
embeddable in any environment (one example is PX Webapp + Spring).</li>
<li>More flexible, see <a href="configuration.html">configuration</a>.</li>
<li>Out-of-the-box able to differentiate Maven1/2 Snapshots, Maven2 metadata
and POMs and set expiration on them  by type or refetch them always.</li>
<li>Metadata aware storage, to "decorate" downloaded items with custom
"metadata" key-value pairs used for processing or tagging.</li>
<li>Flexible logic implementations. Different repos may have different retrieval
logic, as per Repository configuration allows.</li>
<li>Uses <b>Apache Lucene</b> as a search engine for cached items.</li>
<li>Not fighting against WAR deployment (Sincerely, I need WAR, since one Tomcat
already runs in my office).</li>
</ul>

<p>You can see Proximity in action <a href="/proximity">here</a>!</p>

</subsection>

<subsection name="Project reports">
<p>Navigate with links on the left to examine current project status, various project reports
and latest changes.</p>
</subsection>

</section>

</body>
</document>
